Finding aid to the Maude Bushnell Green papers. SSC.MS.00187
Sophia Smith Collection
Maude Bushnell Green papers
1900-1978
Sophia Smith Collection
Green, Maude Bushnell
SSC.MS.00187
6 boxes (2.5 linear feet)
Teacher, history; Traveler; Farmer. Papers contain correspondence with her mother and husband; correspondence and memorabilia from her sons and memorabilia while at Amherst College and Harvard, circa 1930s; travel diaries describe trips around the world, and in Europe, the U.S., Mexico, Australia, and New Zealand (circa 1920s-70s); and records from "Faraway Farm" (Pomfret Center, Connecticut).
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for use without restriction beyond the standard terms and conditions of Smith College Special Collections.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Murray H. Green in 1985. This collection is comprised of the following accessions, some of which may not have accession records. Accession numbers: 85-26.
Biographical / Historical
Born in Brooklyn, New York, daughter of Hattie Edna Galinger and Frederick Johnson Bushnell. She earned her A.B. from Smith College in 1910 and was a high school history teacher in New York City, 1910-11. Married Clarence Green, 1911, and had 2 sons, Frederick B. and Murray H. Green, both Amherst College graduates, and Brooklyn Law School and Harvard Business Schools, respectively. Maude Bushnell Green bought "Faraway Farm" in Pomfret Center, Connecticut in 1941 and lived there from World War II until 1972. She traveled extensively. She died on February 22, 1984.
Scope and Contents
Papers contain primarily family correspondence and diaries. Correspondence includes letters to and from her mother, Hattie, and her husband, Clarence, and correspondence and memorabilia from her sons and memorabilia while at Amherst College and Harvard, circa 1930s. The diaries fall into three categories: general diaries from 1900-1905 and 1931-39. Green and her family were avid travelers and there are 19 travel diaries describing trips to Europe, Australia, New Zealand and around the world, as well as the United States, dating from 1925-1955. In addition, there are diaries, an almanac, notes and accounts for Faraway Farm, Pomfret Center, Connecticut, 1941-1972, a farm the Greens bought in 1941, which became their permanent home early in WWII. Memorabilia consists of a "Literary Weekly" edited by Maude Bushnell in 1902, a notebook of her earnings from 1937-1951, and miscellaneous school material of Murray and Frederick Green.
Australia--Description and travel--Sources; Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)--History--Sources; Farm life--Connecticut--History--20th century--Sources; Mexico--Description and travel--Sources; New Zealand--Description and travel--Sources; notebooks; Europe-Description and travel-Sources; Account books.; memorabilia; correspondence; scrapbooks; diaries; United States--Description and travel--Sources; Amherst College--Students--History--Sources; Bushnell family; Faraway Farm (Pomfret Center, Conn.); Green family; Green, Murray H.; Green, Maude Bushnell
- SERIES I: Correspondence
  - Maude Bushnell Green to Hattie Bushnell, 1925; no date (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Maude Bushnell Green to Clarence Green, 1925; 1929-1933 (Box 1, Folder 2-6)
  - Hattie Bushnell to Maude Bushnell Green, 1926; 1928; no date (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Clarence Green to Maude Bushnell Green (with enclosures from Frederick and Murray), 1935 (Box 1, Folder 8-11)
  - Frederick Green to family members, 1929-1940 (Box 1, Folder 12-22)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence and enclosures from Frederick Green, 1924-1934; no date (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Murray Green to family members, 1931-1954 (Box 2, Folder 24-41)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence to Murray Green, 1935 (Box 2, Folder 42)
- SERIES II: Diaries and Scrapbooks
  - Diaries (7), 1900-1905; 1931-1935; 1939 (Box 3)
  - Scrapbook, 1911-1912 (Box 3)
  - Travel diaries, Europe (8) (Maude Bushnell Green, Helen Bushnell), 1925-1931 (Box 4)
  - Travel diaries, Round the world (2), 1935 (Box 4)
  - Travel diaries, Australia, New Zealand (1), 1965-1966 (Box 4)
  - Travel diaries, Europe (5) (Frederick Green), 1925-1935 (Box 4)
  - Travel diaries, United States (3), 1933-1940; 1954-1955 (Box 4)
  - Faraway Farm, Accounts, 1945-1946; 1965 (Box 5)
  - Faraway Farm, Almanac, 1942-1946 (Box 5)
  - Faraway Farm, Guestbook, 1941-1972 (Box 5)
  - Faraway Farm, Diary, 1941-1944 (Box 5)
  - Faraway Farm, Engagements, 1955 (Box 5)
  - Faraway Farm, Notes, 1945 (Box 5)
  - Faraway Farm, Miscellaneous material from looseleaf notebook, 1941-1944 (Box 5)
- SERIES III: Memorabilia
  - "Literary Weekly," edited by Maude Bushnell, 1902 (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - Maude Green's earnings, 1937-1951 (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - Amherst College material (Murray Green), 1930-1935 (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - Harvard and Amherst College material (Murray and Frederick Green), 1934-1940 (Box 6, Folder 45)